Sophia Marousis

Butler, NJ

Phone: (973) 220-0402 | Email: marousiss@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/marousiss | LinkedIn: https://github.com/marousiss | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sophiamarousis/

Portfolio: https://marousiss.github.io/sophia-marousis-portfolio/

Summary

Full-stack web developer recently with a certificate in full-stack web development from Rutgers University. Highly motivated problem solver effectively using my technical skills to design, build, and maintain websites according to the specifications. Self-directed professional with extensive experience in all phases of the software development life cycle, seeks to bring talent and technical expertise to a respected organization that values strong work ethic, solid critical thinking skills, and results.

Technical Skills

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, React

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, Shell &

Batch scripting

Concepts: APIs, REST, MVC, TDD, JSON

Tools: Git, Github, Heroku, VS Code

Projects

Cuisine and Recipes Logbook

https://github.com/francescortuna/cuisine-and-recipes-logbook | https://guarded-basin-90757.herokuapp.com/

- A CMS style blog site for cuisines and recipes.
- Designed and built the app in collaboration with team group members.
- Skills Used: JavaScript, BootStrap, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, APIs, MVC, Git, GitHub, and Heroku.

Random Movie Generator | https://github.com/faye3091/Movie-Randomizer | https://faye3091.github.io/Movie-Randomizer/

- Movie randomizer app that picks a movie randomly from the top 250 movies of the IMDB library.
- Designed and built the app in collaboration with team group members.
- Skills Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, APIs, Git, and GitHub.

Experience

Sweet Greek Bites Donut Shop Manager

2016 - 2018 Los Angeles, CA

- Ran day to day store operations with accuracy and efficiency
- Communicated with vendors on new orders
- Managed and oversaw work schedules of store employees
- Compiled with safety regulations
- Handled Bank reconciliations and other accounting tasks effectively and effectively

Greek Orthodox Youth of America (GOYA) Saint Constantine and Helen Greek Orthodox Church Chaperone

2009 - 2015 Orange, NJ

- Supervised young adults during various activities to ensure safety & follow guidelines and protocols
- Provided transportation to different activity locations
- Attended weekly meetings of the coming events
- Participated, organized in donation drives to help fundraise for organization

Olympic Computer Services Programmer Analyst

2004 - 2009

Fairfield, NJ

- Designed, developed, coded, tested, and debugged software programs, interfaces, and reports using Visual Basic to support migration from legacy system
- Gathered and analyzed system requirements from key users, translating them into technical specifications
- Reported routinely on project status and resolved technical issues

BASF Corporation SAP ABAP Developer

1998 - 2004

Mount Olive, NJ

- Designed, developed, tested, modified, expanded, maintained, and supported software applications, interactive reports, and interfaces using SAP ABAP, with specific attention to Material Management (MM), Sales & Distribution (SD), and Financial Accounting/Controlling(FI/CO) modules
- Worked with functional leads, users, and other technical team members to analyze functional requirements and translate them into technical solutions
- Designed and modified SAP Script and Smart Forms
- Enhanced SAP program Functionality and resolved technical issues reported by users
- Coded and uploaded legacy files to support transition to SAP

Education

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate: Rutgers Bootcamps, Newark, NJ February 2023

A 24 week Intensive full stack development focussed on gaining skills in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JSON, Node.JS, APIs, MySQL, MongoDB, and React

Master of Science in Computer Science: Fairleigh Dickinson University, Teaneck, NJ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science: Montclair State University, Montclair, NJ